

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a recent Grand Circus graduate with certification in front end web development. Before Grand Circus I worked as a child care specialist and developed lasting meaningful relationships with the families while doing self-exploration on my own time. I had already been dabbling with coding and when I was afforded more free time due to the pandemic, I dove deeper into coding, finding I truly enjoyed it and was good at it. My work with children 2 and under has helped me develop a unique level of patience which combined with my empathy for others are distinct characteristics that I think will help me go far as a developer.

CONTACT

Phone:

269-760-3044

Email:

TaylerAnnOndersma@gmail.com

GitHub | LinkedIn | Website

VOLUNTEER

Starfish Family Services American Friends Service Committee Interfaith Hospitality Network

Front End Web Developer

EDUCATION

- Front-End Bootcamp | 2021

 Jack White Memory Game: <u>GitHub-Link</u>; <u>Playable-Link</u>
 - View all projects

Bachelor's Degree | May 2017

• Double major in Psychology and Sociology

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Angular
- Git/GitHub
- TypeScript
- SQL
- Web APIs
- Bootstrap
- Wireframing
- Scrum
- Node.is

WORK EXPERIENCE

Child Development Specialist/Nanny | Nov 2017 - Jan 2021

- Helped children reach developmental milestones through:
 - · educational play and reading
 - One-on-one tutoring and attending classes together like "Fun at One" through the First Steps program offered by AAPS
 - enriching outings (i.e. museums, parks, etc.)
 - Worked with families to develop individualized plans to best meet the needs of each unique child

Lab Manager | June 2016 - July 2017

- Oversaw operations of the lab including but were not limited to:
 - o daily check-ins on 3 or more ongoing research projects and with 5 plus graduate students
 - Placing orders for various lab supplies and managing S100s in
 - Conducting research assistant interviews and trained more than ten new research assistants
 - Preparing for periodic reviews to ensure/protect the welfare of human subjects

Research Assistant | June 2015 - June 2016

- Recruited/scheduled hundreds of participants via email and phone communication
- Administered hundreds of cognitive and diagnostic tests then recorded, scored, and interpreted data into a database containing thousands of participants
- Paid participants for their participation with lab funds